[
    {
        "question": "Which protocol is used to transfer web pages?",
        "answer": "HTTP"
    },
    {
        "question": "What programming language is popular in data science?",
        "answer": "Python"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the program called that you use to surf the internet?",
        "answer": "Browser"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the standard markup language for creating web pages?",
        "answer": "HTML"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Python, what keyword is used to define a function?",
        "answer": "def"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the file extension for Python files?",
        "answer": ".py"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Python, which keyword is used to exit a loop?",
        "answer": "break"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which OS uses Tux as its mascot?",
        "answer": "Linux"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company developed Android?",
        "answer": "Google"
    },
    {
        "question": "What language is used to manage databases?",
        "answer": "SQL"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company produces 'ThinkPad'?",
        "answer": "Lenovo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which operating system is developed by Apple?",
        "answer": "macOS"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cloud computing service is developed by Amazon?",
        "answer": "AWS"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest unit of data in computing?",
        "answer": "Bit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which HTTP status code means 'Page Not Found'?",
        "answer": "404"
    },
    {
        "question": "What command checks the network connectivity between two systems?",
        "answer": "Ping"
    },
    {
        "question": "What network device manages multiple VLANs?",
        "answer": "Switch"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a secure LAN connection through an insecure network called?",
        "answer": "VPN"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Bluetooth technology enables payment and data exchange via a mobile phone?",
        "answer": "NFC"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many bits does an IPv4 address consist of?",
        "answer": "32"
    }
]
